

RIDOAN KHAN ANIK

S O F T W A R E E N G I N E E R



157/A Distillery Road, Gandaria, Dhaka - 1204



0186-1858938



ridoankhan07@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/ridoankhananik



github.com/ridoankhan



hackerrank.com/ridoankhan07



A result-driven and dedicated Software Engineer with one year of experience in research, development, testing and implementing production level Blockchain DApps and web applications. Seeking for a challenging Software Engineer position where I can further enhance my knowledge and continue developing applications with forthcoming technologies.



🚣 SOFT SKILLS

Quick-Learner

Work Under Pressure

Responsible

Team-Player

Public-Speaking



TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Language: C, C++, Node.js, Java
- Blockchain Technologies: Hyperledger-Fabric, Ethereum, Solidity, Smart-Contract, Web3, Truffle, Ganache
- Database: Oracle 11g, MS SQL Server (2008, 2012, 2014), MongoDB, Firebase
- Web Languages and Scripts: HTML-5, CSS-3, SCSS, Bootstrap—4, JavaScript, jQuery
- **Operating System:** Linux (Ubuntu, Kali, SUSE), Windows 2000 / XP, Vista, Win7, Win8, Win10
- Office packages: MS Word, MS Excel, Power Point
- Tools: VS Code, Eclipse IDE, Swagger, Docker
- Version Control System: Git



EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Leads Corporation Limited



FEB. 2019 - PRESENT



Dhaka, Bangladesh

Responsibilities

- Research and development of blockchain-based applications on Ethereum and Hyperledger Fabric platform
- Research and develop prototypes for blockchain and IoT applications and reengineering according to client requirements
- Establishing and maintaining the environments in which blockchain solutions are implemented (development, testing, production)
- Develop eco-system for IoT based systems by establishing proper communication between IoT devices and backend applications by designing database, handlers, APIs and frontend applications.

Junior Developer (Intern) Providence Tech Sdn Bhd



Apr. 2018 - Aug. 2018



Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Responsibilities

- Designing front-end for web applications
- API development using Laravel
- Developing user interface for mobile application according to given design using react-native
- Updating contents on live website and edit design
- Developing smart contracts using solidity on Ropsten test network



EDUCATION



Bachelor of Information Technology (Hons)



Oct. 2014 - Aug. 2018



Nilai University, Putra, Malaysia



Result - 3.63 out of 4.00



👶 LeadsTrack – Blockchain based Supply Chain Monitoring **System**

- **Description** Distributed app to for supply chain to trace and authenticate valuable asset. Manufacturer can track every handover of product until it reaches customer as well as enabling the customer to easily verify product originality using simple QR scanner. Prevents selling fake products in the market and keeps track of every fake product that has been reported.
- Technologies Used: Hyperledger Fabric-1.2, IBM Cloud, Node.js, MongoDB

Pharmachain (BASIS National ICT Award Winning Runner-up Project 2019)

- Description A pharmaceutical system for tracking and authentication system based on Hyperledger Composer for any pharmaceutical drugs.
- Technologies Used: Hyperledger Composer, Node.js, MongoDB

🛟 Environment Monitoring Device

- **Description** A device monitors the internal environment of an office or organization that can detect potential elements in the environment and alert the user anything goes wrong. The device can be controlled from a web application and see potential analytical data about the environment.
- Technologies Used: Microcontroller, sensors, MQTT, Node.js, MongoDB, C++

Nimble – IoT Office Automation Platform

- Description True human presence and MESH topology-based automation, monitoring and indoor navigation platform. Controlling appliances, monitoring environment automatically and remotely.
- Technologies Used: Microcontroller, sensors, MQTT, Node.js, MongoDB, C++, Wi-Fi module

Secured Decentralized Cloud based Key Management System **Using Steganography**

- **Description** Tool for small organization to effectively manage encryption keys in a decentralized cloud where the data integrity and confidentiality is assured with aggregated encryption techniques that includes-SHA256 and Least Significant Bits (LSB).
- Technologies Used: Python, Cryptography, SHA-256

ACHIEVEMENTS



Best Student Award

Convocation 2019, Nilai University, Putra, Malaysia



Deans' List Award

May 2016, January 2016, Nilai University



Leadership Development Program

May 2017, Outward Bound Malaysia



CERTIFICATIONS



IBM Blockchain Foundation Developer

IBM Blockchain Platform



Build an IoT Blockchain Network for a Supply Chain

IBM Blockchain Platform



Blockchain Essentials

Cognitive Class, IBM Online Certification



LANGUAGES

Bangla



English





REFERENCES

Associate Professor Dr. Abbas Mehdizadeh Zare Anari

(Associate Professor at Department of Computing, Nilai University)

🔀 abbas@nilai.edu.my

+6012-6234351

Kamrul Hasan

(Software Engineer - Leads Corporation Limited)



kamrul hasan@leads-bd.com

+880 1672 145347